<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>empowering on Jeronimo Barbosa</title>
    <link>/tags/empowering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in empowering on Jeronimo Barbosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Jeronimo Barbosa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/empowering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>StateSynth</title>
      <link>/project/statesynth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/statesynth/</guid>
      <description>Musicians devote years developing instrumental skills to achieve mastery of musical instruments. Yet, domain-specific end-user programming environments remain (i) often centered on mouse and keyboard as primitive input method and (ii) poorly designed for incorporating these expert instrumental skills as input.
Attempting to explore this issue, I proposed the StateSynth.
StateSynth is a direct manipulation-based music authoring environment where the keyboard becomes a central programming primitive, empowering musicians to build personal interactive musical tools based on their keyboard skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steal &amp; Repeat Machine</title>
      <link>/project/steal-and-repeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/steal-and-repeat/</guid>
      <description>The Steal &amp;amp; Repeat Machine is a live looping tool based on direct manipulation of sound.   The Steal &amp;amp; Repeat Machine consists of an iPad physically extended via a plexiglass case equipped with an external sound card and two knob controls for phasing and feedback.
The iPad runs a software interface implemented in C++/Openframeworks, presented below:
   Some examples of the Steal &amp;amp; Repeat in action:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusio Looping Machine</title>
      <link>/project/illusio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/illusio/</guid>
      <description>Illusio is a live looping tool that enables musicians to sketch their own loop controls in a multitouch table. Illusio has received the support of Rumos Itaú Cultural Arte Cibernética 2009, and was shortlisted in the Interaction Design Association (IxDA) Interaction Awards 2013.
   The Illusio was prototyped in Processing and Openframeworks, in 2011. More information can be found on my old website.
Some video material presenting the Illusio and its motivation:     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>