<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>speculative on Jeronimo Barbosa</title>
    <link>/tags/speculative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in speculative on Jeronimo Barbosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Jeronimo Barbosa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/speculative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Insertions into Mediatic Circuits</title>
      <link>/project/insertions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/insertions/</guid>
      <description>1) There are in society certain mecanisms for circulation (circuits);
2) These circuits clearly reflect the ideology of the producer, but at the same time it is possible they could receive insertions while they circulate;
3) This always happen whenever someone starts it.
Cildo Meireles, 1970.
 &amp;ldquo;Insertions into Mediatic Circuits&amp;rdquo; were a series of short media interventions (insertions) where social networks&amp;rsquo; live video streams were copied, modified, and finally streamed back to social networks in realtime, while the original live stream still occurred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>29 de Abril</title>
      <link>/project/29-de-abril/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/29-de-abril/</guid>
      <description>In April 29th 2015, in Curitiba, Brazil, more than 200 people were hurt (mostly civilian teachers) as a result from a brutal action from the police forces, following direct orders from Paraná state&amp;rsquo;s government.
The institutional violence made headlines in Brazilian and international media. Teachers were protesting against reforms on their social security system when the police attacked with bombs and plastic bullets. More than 15 policemen refused to attack and were arrested, threatened with dismissal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executable memories (Paris.py)</title>
      <link>/project/paris-py/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/paris-py/</guid>
      <description>Executable Memories (Paris.py) are 18 personal poems written in Python programming language, documenting people, places, and moments lived during a six-months trip in 2012. These code-poems are personal memories intended to be run in obsolete computers.
from Paris import * &#39;&#39;&#39; INTRODUCTION &#39;&#39;&#39; a_kid with silicon_skin() and liquid_crystal_eyes(): came(to_me_last_night) she wept_blood() and offered_me(sweet_coltan_roses) while holding(a_twisted_pair_leash) in her_left_hand: plugged(into_the_brain, of_a_cerberus_shaped_cyborg) which_barked_in_binary_code(&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;how could you forget again what was invented and what was discovered?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ada v2.0b</title>
      <link>/project/ada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ada/</guid>
      <description>Ada v2.0b is a Python-written programmer machine that live codes sound in Pure Data. Its performances are based on the activity of its own kernel. Ada has been presented in Live Cinema Festival 2010 and on GLI.TC/H 2010. More information in my old website.
   Ada was developed using Pyata—a Python module I wrote back in 2009 to allow people to dynamically create and edit Pure Data patchs via dynamic patching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marvim Gainsbug</title>
      <link>/project/marvim-gainsbug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/marvim-gainsbug/</guid>
      <description>Marvim Gainsbug is a chatbot that gathers social network messages to improvise live music, with lyrics and harmony. It was developed in collaboration with Filipe Calegario, in 2009.
Marvim has received an honorable mention in the FILE PRIX LUX 2010, awarded the Prêmio Conexões tecnológicas, and was presented in several venues in Brazil.
More information in my old website.
     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>