<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Jeronimo Barbosa</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Jeronimo Barbosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Jeronimo Barbosa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>StateSynth</title>
      <link>/project/statesynth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/statesynth/</guid>
      <description>StateSynth is a direct manipulation-based music authoring environment where the keyboard becomes a central programming primitive, empowering musicians to build personal interactive musical tools based on their keyboard skills. For example:
  How it works? StateSynth uses a visual specification model based on hierarchical finite-states machines that was developed as part of my Ph.D. (details here). The model is called ZenStates:
  
A detailed introduction to StateSynth can be found on the next videos:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steal &amp; Repeat Machine</title>
      <link>/project/steal-and-repeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/steal-and-repeat/</guid>
      <description>The Steal &amp;amp; Repeat Machine is a live looping tool based on direct manipulation of sound.   The Steal &amp;amp; Repeat Machine consists of an iPad physically extended via a plexiglass case equipped with an external sound card and two knob controls for phasing and feedback.
The iPad runs a software interface implemented in C++/Openframeworks, presented below:
   Some examples of the Steal &amp;amp; Repeat in action:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batebit</title>
      <link>/project/batebit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/batebit/</guid>
      <description>Batebit started as a research project focused on designing music performance interfaces for popular music communities in the Northeastern Brazil—a collaboration between João Tragtenberg, Filipe Calegario, and myself. I proudly contributed to Batebit between 2013 and 2015. Since then, Batebit follows active under the inspiring work of João and Filipe.
For more information, check Batebit website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusio Looping Machine</title>
      <link>/project/illusio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/illusio/</guid>
      <description>Illusio is a live looping tool that enables musicians to sketch their own loop controls in a multitouch table. Illusio has received the support of Rumos Itaú Cultural Arte Cibernética 2009, and was shortlisted in the Interaction Design Association (IxDA) Interaction Awards 2013.
   The Illusio was prototyped in Processing and Openframeworks, in 2011. More information can be found on my old website.
Some video material presenting the Illusio and its motivation:     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>