<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Jeronimo Barbosa</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Jeronimo Barbosa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. Jeronimo Barbosa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>StateSynth</title>
      <link>/project/statesynth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/statesynth/</guid>
      <description>StateSynth is a direct music authoring system where the keyboard becomes a central programming primitive. As a result, musicians can easily, for example: use intervals to dynamically control the delay time of a sinusoidal oscillator; or yet play specific chords to switch between different synthesizer presets.
StateSynth uses ZenStates as specification model:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steal &amp; Repeat Machine</title>
      <link>/project/steal-and-repeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/steal-and-repeat/</guid>
      <description>The Steal &amp;amp; Repeat Machine is a live looping tool based on direct manipulation of sound. The software interface, implemented in C++/Openframeworks, is presented below:
   The tablet is physically embedded inside an acrylic case equipped with an external sound card and physical controls. These physical controls enable feedback, phasing, and pitch adjustments:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Batebit</title>
      <link>/project/batebit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/batebit/</guid>
      <description>Batebit started as a research project focused on designing music performance interfaces for popular music communities in the Northeastern Brazil—a collaboration between João Tragtenberg, Filipe Calegario, and myself. I proudly contributed to Batebit between 2013 and 2015. Since then, Batebit follows active under the inspiring work of João and Filipe.
For more information, check Batebit website:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illusio Looping Machine</title>
      <link>/project/illusio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/illusio/</guid>
      <description>Illusio is a live looping tool that enables musicians to sketch their own loop controls in a multitouch table. Illusio has received the support of Rumos Itaú Cultural Arte Cibernética 2009, and was shortlisted in the Interaction Design Association (IxDA) Interaction Awards 2013.
   The Illusio was prototyped in Processing and Openframeworks, in 2011. More information can be found on my old website.
Some video material presenting the Illusio and its motivation:     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>